Jack: What is meant by
an Agile development?
We have already mentioned ‘Agile’ in
previous units but now let’s look at it
in more detail and see how this process
is used for software development.
Leah: ‘Agile Development’ which is
also more commonly known as Agile
Software Development, is an umbrella
term for a range of frameworks,
such as ‘Scrum’, and practices such
as the ‘daily stand-up meeting’.
It adopts the principles set
out in the ‘Agile Manifesto’
and the ‘Agile 12 Principles’.
Agile came about as a process to
address issues that software developers
faced, focussing on a project being
flexible, so it could respond to any
changes and deal with any uncertainty.
Jack: Agile is people-oriented and
result-focused in respect to software
delivery and instead of delivering all
the product at the end of the project,
the software is built incrementally
from the start in time-boxed 'sprints'.
It is an iterative approach used in
software development projects with a
focus on continuous releases that takes
customer feedback into consideration.
So, how does this work?
Development tasks are broken down into
bite size chunks, which can be achieved
in a certain period known as a ‘sprint’.
The agile team itself would normally
consist of different skillsets, working
independently and collaboratively, to
achieve the tasks within that set time.
Leah: Let’s now look at the ‘Agile
Manifesto’ and how it originated.
The Agile Manifesto is a short document,
which was created in 2001 from a group of
leading professionals who met to discuss
the future of software development.
Its focus is on value to individuals and
interactions, working software, customer
collaboration and responding to change.
The Manifesto itself is short and
made up of 68 words and has since
been embraced by many different teams
and companies, and it is agreed by
many that it is still relevant today.
Jack: What are the 12 Principles?
The 12 Principles of Agile Software,
expand on the values within the Manifesto.
The focus is on the customer,
continuous delivery of product,
change, frequency, team collaboration,
motivation, support, communication,
measurement, excellence, simplicity,
self-organisation, and reflection.
To read more about this, see
the full Manifesto and the 12
principles in the document and
weblinks provided below this video.